Hatem Ben Hamza

PHP developer

PERSONAL SUMMARY

A highly resourceful, innovative, and competent PHP developer with good experience in the layout, design and coding of websites specifically in PHP format. Possessing considerable knowledge of the development of web applications and scripts using PHP programming language and MySQL & SQL Server databases.

Experienced in developing applications and solutions for a wide range of corporate, charity and public sector clients and having the enthusiasm and ambition to complete projects to the highest standard.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Micromad Solution - Italian Multinational premium web firm *Full Stack Web Developer June 2018 - Present

Working with designers, Front End and project management staff to capture requirements for the functional elements of website projects. Also responsible for liaising with clients and ensuring that all work carried out complies with standards and guidelines.

Duties:

- Building PHP websites using PHP based frameworks.(Symfony)
- Planning and conducting cross-browser usability testing against W3C.
- Testing and validating work produced as part of the development process.
- Developing advanced database driven websites & systems including ecommerce.
- Back end development and maintenance of websites using PHP and MySQL.
- Developing compatible User Interface functionality using jQuery & other libraries.
- Developing web sites using MySQL, PHP, ASP.NET & other programming tools.
- Working in a data analyst role and with business intelligence applications.
- Documenting features, technical specifications & infrastructure requirements.
- Working with a multi-disciplinary team to convert business needs into technical specifications.

Formalab - Training center

"Offering an offer of more than 50 continuing education programs for students, executives of companies, as well as professional organizations and design offices". *Symfony Trainer October 2018 – Present

Freelance 2016 – Present

'I am developer. I am a programmer with good knowledge of front-end and backend techniques, have more than 2 years of experience in developing web applications.'

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Ability to multi-task, react quickly to shifting priorities and meet deadlines.
- Proactive, confident and with a positive "can-do" attitude.
- Able to clearly communicate technical data to non-technical colleagues and clients.
- Continuously monitoring industry trends, technologies and standards.
- Possessing all-round analysis and programming skills.
- Methodical yet creative & having a proven ability for efficient problem solving.
- Excellent attention to detail both front and back end.
- Solid web development experience using OOP, PHP, AJAX, MySQL, JavaScript, XML, HTML and CSS.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

Information Technology BSc (Hons)

Higher Institute of Information Technologies and Communications (ISTIC) Tunisia 2015 - 2018

REFERENCES – Available on request.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Commercial experience

Web developing / programming

PHP MVC Frameworks

CMS implementation (WordPress, Joomla, etc.)

Server administration

Object Orientated Programming

Software graphics manipulation

AWARDS

IBM Big Data Developer Mastery Award certificate

PERSONAL SKILLS

Time management

Goals orientated

Ability to grasp concepts quickly

LANGUAGES













PERSONAL DETAILS

Hatem Ben Hamza 03 sidi bouzid street Hammam-Lif Tunis Tunisia (216) 58 703 765 hatembenhamza96@gmail .com

DOB: 14/07/1996 Driving license: Yes Nationality: Tunisian